aside from money versatility may be the
most important factor when it comes to
adding new equipment to a home gym now
we've seen a lot of innovative products
on the market lately but one product in
particular that has really stood out to
me is the monkey feet from Animal House
now I'm sure you've seen these on the
internet but if you don't really know
what these are not familiar with them
this simple product fits around your
foot and holds a dumbbell of your
choosing and allows you to work your
legs in multiple different ways I've
been using these a lot lately and I'm
pretty excited to break them down for
y'all
[Music]
what's up everybody it's Jake back in
the barbin garage gym and for today's
video I've got a pair of monkey feet
from Animal House now in this video I'm
gonna break this product down for you
from the price the features some pros
and cons you may run into and of course
who should or maybe should not purchase
some of these okay so before I get going
with all of that I gotta let you know
since these do in fact work in tandem
with dumbbells which are technically
free weights we've reviewed a lot of
free weights on barbin.com so if you
want to browse our best list just go and
search bar Bend best free weights our
article is going to pull up for you and
you can find out for yourself which ones
that we like the best
[Music]
okay so I want to talk about a few
things I like about the monkey feet
first of all they're extremely easy for
you to use and it's really
straightforward so all you got to do is
take a dumbbell toss it in this groove
right here it's going to clamp down and
then you just strap your foot in you
have a bit of a snowboard binding strap
right here for you to you know ratchet
it in and keep your foot tight and
you're good to go you're ready to start
working out they're also extremely
versatile so one of these monkey feet
right here it's going to allow you to do
leg curls leg extensions you can work on
your hip flexors you can also work your
abductors and your adductors there's a
lot you can do with just one of these
monkey feet and that's really nice
they're also pretty cheap you know so
one of these is only going to run you
about 80 bucks and considering the
versatility I think that's a pretty you
know solid purchase you can get two like
we have but I don't really think you
necessarily need to because they're
Universal with your feet doesn't matter
which one you put it on so that's really
nice they're also one size fits all up
to a size 14 in men's so that's really
nice too plus you can hold up to 160
pounds of weight with one of these and
that's a really solid number in my
opinion you know I don't know too many
people who have 160 pound dumbbells or
even a kettlebell at home so odds are
this is going to work just fine for you
throughout your fitness journey
[Music]
now there's not a ton of cons here with
this product but there's still a couple
I want to bring to your attention some
of you might run into this let's talk
about the universal size first you know
if you have a shoe size larger than a
men's 14 this product is just simply not
going to work it's not going to fit your
foot so you know definitely keep that in
mind and save your money and another
thing here is you know the first time
you toss them on your feet they're gonna
feel a little bit clunky a little funky
you know it's going to be a little weird
but that's definitely something you can
get used to over time and also in my
opinion you know they're not as smooth
as a machine is which is what they're
trying to replace right here so you're
really going to have to have a strong
emphasis on having perfect form which
you definitely always should you don't
want to get hurt you want to do your
exercises the right way but I think
that's especially true with the monkey
feed
[Music]
okay so once again you can purchase one
of these monkey feet for right around 80
bucks you can get the pair if you want
for around 150 but honestly you know one
of these is just going to work perfectly
fine for you so 80 bucks you know that's
a really solid deal especially if you're
tight on Space you live in a small
apartment whatever it is you have some
adjustable dumbbells maybe you know you
do have a full dumbbell set these are
going to work great with that so I think
80 bucks is a really solid price
foreign
[Music]
now since this is a pretty
straightforward product you know there's
not a whole lot going on in terms of the
build and the features but you know me I
still got to talk about it a little bit
so these are in fact made of plastic the
only way a pound may be a little bit
more than a pound they're also Universal
in terms of shoe size up to a men's 14
and you can use it on either foot
doesn't matter now you have a snowboard
binding style clamp right here which is
really easy to use and I just you know
kind of like it I like the noise it
makes it's just it's pretty cool so
these are going to hold up to 160 pounds
of weight which is really solid in my
opinion and in terms of working with
dumbbells the minimum width you can use
on the handle you know of your your
dumbbells is five inches and in terms of
diameter the max width you can have is
right around 37 millimeters so these are
going to work with the majority of
dumbbells out there which is you know
really nice you don't have to go and
necessarily buy something special just
to work with this product right here
foreign
take a minute and just you know break
this down up close for you guys and kind
of demonstrate how everything works so
as you can see you know once you're done
using it it's pretty easy to store it
you know it's nice and Compact and it's
not going to take up you know a bunch of
space if you want to throw in a backpack
take it on the road with you whatever
but you're also going to get a
complimentary bag with your purchase so
that's really nice too okay so let's
talk about how everything actually
functions so I've noticed it's easier to
actually you know get the dumbbell and
everything set up when it's still
clamped down like this so you're gonna
want that dumbbell to go in this hook
and then you know this strap right here
reminds me of my bindings my snowboard
as I mentioned you just pull up on this
tab and that's going to come undone for
you so what happens is whenever you pull
this back side up that clamp right there
it's gonna it's gonna really clamp that
dumbbell in so put it in
and I'll show you right here pull this
up and then boom it's not going to come
out you also have some padding that goes
on the inside of the actual monkey foot
you know it's gonna be really nice it
goes up against the back of your foot
and your Achilles and everything it's
also on the top as well that way it
doesn't feel like plastic is just
digging into your foot as you're working
out so now we're just going to go ahead
place it on the ground
put my foot in get everything set up
where you want it to be
and then you're good to go and you can
pull this right here and that's going to
tighten everything up to your own
Comfort level and then once you do that
I mean it's really simple you can do
whatever you want to do sit here and do
your leg extensions you can lay down and
do your leg curls I'll go and do that
for you guys real quick
you know you sit here and do your leg
curls
whatever it is you're wanting to do now
one thing I noticed whenever I started
going up the weight is that the overall
size of the dumbbell heads is gonna be
important so
as you can see I got a 25 pound Dumbo
right here and you know after just you
know a handful of uses it started you
know rubbing on this rubber right here
and kind of scratched it and caused a
little bit of damage so definitely keep
that in mind you know might not happen
with every single dumbbell but it
happened with me so it definitely could
happen with you another thing here is
that
yeah I can definitely sit here and do my
leg extensions but this bench isn't that
tall so if that's something you run into
you know luckily I have another bench
right here beside me where this seat is
able to come up
and that gives me that ample room I need
my foot actually dangles a little bit
and I'm really able to do my leg
extensions that way now really easy to
take off
pull up
and it comes out and then you can kind
of close it again and that's going to
come right out for you it's really easy
to use you can switch your weight in
just a matter of seconds
[Music]
thank you
okay so who should purchase the monkey
feet well if you're looking for a really
versatile product this is about as good
as it gets right here you're able to do
leg curls leg extensions work on your
hip flexors work on your abductors and
your abductors there's a lot you can do
right here and you can mimic machines
that you would find in the gym so if
you're tight on space at home you know
it's gonna be really good for you now
another thing here is that they're
relatively cheap you know 80 bucks for
one of these is going to be really nice
especially since you can do so much with
them
[Music]
and when it comes to those who might not
want to purchase these it's really
simple you know first of all we gotta
talk about the overall feel if it's
something you can't get used to or
something you just don't like and then
you're probably gonna be better off you
know going to the gym and using you know
some type of machine there instead of
you know trying to mimic that with one
of these and then also shoe size if your
shoe size is bigger than a men's 14 then
this simply is just not going to work
for you
[Music]
well that's all I have for you guys
today on the monkey feet you know I've
been seeing these all over the Internet
like I mentioned earlier I'm sure you
have two to be honest I was a bit of a
skeptic at first and over time I've
grown to really enjoy these you know
they work my entire legs you know
hammies to my quads to my hip flexors I
mean there's a lot you can do with these
so if you're tight on Space you know
this is going to be really nice for you
and they're relatively cheap about 80
bucks for one of them is not bad at all
yes they're made of plastic but you know
honestly they feel pretty sturdy they
feel pretty solid in my hands just
remember you know if you have a shoe
size bigger than a men's 14 this just
simply is not going to work for you
thanks for watching everybody I hope
this video was super helpful that I was
able to break down everything you need
to know about the monkey feet as always
stay posted for my next video but for
now head over to barbin.com and you can
read more about this product all you
gotta do is search bar Bend Animal House
monkey feet review and you'll find all
the details of everything we discussed
here today I'm gonna go get a workout in
I'll catch y'all next time
[Music]
thank you